HAMZAT HABIBLLAHI ADEWALE

17, Adeniyi street, Agbado Iju-Ishaga road, Lagos https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamzat-habibllahi-8b9542110 https://habibllahi.github.io/personal/ habibllahi3@gmail.com +234[0]8142408496

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE ABEOKUTA (FUNAAB)

2015

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical and Electronics Engineering); second class upper.

OLADIPO ALAYANDE SCHOOL OF SCIENCE

2009

West Africa Senior School Certificate.

SKILLS

Software development

- 1) Programming languages: Java, Kotlin
- 2) Microservice development using Java with spring framework, Tomcat server, Hibernate and MySQL database
- 3) Native Android mobile application development using Kotlin with Android Standard Developmental Kit
- 4) Embedded/Internet of Things development (IoT) using C++ on Arduino and Arduino compactible platforms
- 5) Cross platform desktop application development using Java with JavaFX framework

Electrical

- 1) Mini grid management
- 2) Solar system design and development
- 3) Electrical installation (conduit and surface).
- 4) Solar hybrid installation

ABOUT

I am graduate of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, age 28, with tangible and continuous work experience in both software and renewable energy sector. With respect to software development, I am a JVM programmer with sound knowledge of Java and Kotlin. My carefully chosen software skills are aimed at becoming a senior full-stack android developer.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 29th January 1992, Nationality: Nigerian, State of Origin: Ogun State

Local Government Area: Abeokuta-South, Sex: Male

PRESENTATIONS

Presentation: DESIGN OF INDUSTRIAL BASED TEMPERATURE AND HUMIDITY MONITORING SYSTEM USING EMBEDDED SYSTEM APPROACH FOR HEALTH AND SAFETY.

The Nigerian Universities Engineering Students' Association (NUESA) Conference. 2015. Nigeria.

COMMUNITY SERVICES

National Youth Service Corp (NYSC) teacher

2016 - 2017

Abonnema Girls School, Abonnema, Rivers state, Nigeria

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rubitec Nigeria Limited, Lagos state, Nigeria

2019-Recent

Role: Utility Manager Responsibilities:

- 1) Management of 85KWp solar mini-grid power generation, distribution and consumption
- 2) Monitoring and supervision of power sales
- 3) Sighting of viable communities for Rubitec solar min-grid development and data collection from such communities using Kobo collect tool.
- 4) Installation of solar powered DC system and AC coupled system

Code Trik Nigeria Enterprises

2018 - 2019

Role: Junior software developer

Responsibilities:

Development of micro-services, desktop software and embedded solutions.

HIC MikroLAB, Ogun state, Nigeria

2017 - 2018

Role: Embedded system developer

Responsibilities:

- 1) Design, development and simulation of analogue, digital and embedded system as a control solution.
- 2) Installation of a solar hybrid system as a sustainable and renewable electrical energy source for clients.
- 3) Fundamental electronics trainer.

HIC MikroLAB, Ogun state, Nigeria

2014-2015

Industrial attachment trainee.

Responsibility:

To technically participate in all indoor and outdoor works as a trainee.

Solar power development and installation trainee.

Electronics trainee.

HOBBIES AND LEISURE INTERESTS

- Learning more about microservices and android development.
- Playing mobile video games

MORE ABOUT ME

https://habibllahi.github.io/personal/